<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-button library="ColumnControl">
	<name>order</name>
	<summary>An order trigger and status button</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<description>
		This is perhaps the most common content type used in the examples as ordering is a fundamental part of DataTables. This button is used to both triggering ordering on its host column and also show the status of ordering applied to the column.

		To a large degree it replaces the ordering icons and event handler that DataTables applies to column headers, so you will often use it in combination with `-init ordering.indicators` and `-init ordering.handler` to disable DataTable's default controls.

		When ordering is activated via the button, it follows the same direction application sequence as defined by `-init columns.orderSequence`.

		Examples showing the use of this content type [are available on the DataTables website](https://datatables.net/extensions/columncontrol/examples/ordering/).

		### Display

		Generally this content type will be used at the top level of ColumnControl, thus showing a simple icon button to the end user as it is such a common interaction with the table, but it will also work in a dropdown without issue.
	</description>

	<option type="string" name="iconAsc" default="orderAsc">
		Icon to show when ascending order is applied to the host column. Can take the name of any icon available in `DataTable.ColumnControl.icons` (which is a writeable object containing SVG icons).
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="iconDesc" default="orderDesc">
		Icon to show when descending ordering is applied to the host column. Can take the name of any icon available in `DataTable.ColumnControl.icons`.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="iconNone" default="orderNone">
		Icon to show when there is no order applied to the host column. Can take the name of any icon available in `DataTable.ColumnControl.icons`.
	</option>

	<option type="boolean" name="statusOnly" default="false">
		This option will cause the button not to react to click events when enabled (`true`), and instead simply shows the ordering status of the column.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="text" default="Toggle ordering">
		Trigger button text (shown when in a dropdown). Can also be set by the `orderAsc` key of `-init language.columnControl`, which will take priority if set.
	</option>


	<example title="Simple, single ordering icon in the table headers, replacing the DataTables default."><![CDATA[
new DataTable('#example', {
    columnControl: ['order'],
    ordering: {
        indicators: false,
        handler: false
    }
});
]]></example>

	<example title="Status display only, keeping the DataTables default event handler. Note that `-content orderStatus` is a shorthand for this configuration."><![CDATA[
new DataTable('#example', {
    ordering: {
        indicators: false
    },
    columnControl: [{
		extend: 'order',
		statusOnly: true
	}]
});
]]></example>
</dt-button>
